<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The life of William Fuller, the late pretended evidence now a prisoner in the King's-Bench, who was declared by the Honourable House of Commons, Nemine contradicente, to be a notorious imposter, a cheat, and a false accuser of persons of honour and quality with all his pranks and villainies, &amp;c. to this present first of March.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1692</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 73 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 19 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2012-10">2012-10 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A48422</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing L2039</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R4824</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">12979511</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 12979511</idno>
            <idno type="VID">96168</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A48422)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 96168)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 719:12)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The life of William Fuller, the late pretended evidence now a prisoner in the King's-Bench, who was declared by the Honourable House of Commons, Nemine contradicente, to be a notorious imposter, a cheat, and a false accuser of persons of honour and quality with all his pranks and villainies, &amp;c. to this present first of March.</title>
                  <author>Kingston, Richard, b. 1635?</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[4], 32 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for Abel Roper ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1692.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Dedication signed: A.R.</note>
                  <note>Sometimes attributed to Richard Kingston.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Huntington Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Fuller, William, 1670-1717?</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-07</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-08</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-07</date>
            <label>Holly Beeman</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-07</date>
            <label>Holly Beeman</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-05</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:96168:1"/>
            <p>THE LIFE OF William Fuller, THE Late Pretended EVIDENCE Now a Priſoner in the <hi>King's-Bench.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Who was Declared by the Honourable Houſe of Commons, <hi>Nemine Contradicente,</hi> to be a Notori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous Impoſtor, a Cheat, and a Falſe Accuſer of Perſons of Honour and Quality. With all his Pranks and Villainies, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> to this Preſent Firſt of <hi>March.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed for <hi>Abel Roper,</hi> near <hi>Temple-Bar.</hi> 1692.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="bookseller_to_the_reader">
            <pb facs="tcp:96168:2"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:96168:2"/>
            <head>THE BOOK-SELLER TO THE READER.</head>
            <opener>
               <salute>Gentlemen,</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>NOT to Flouriſh in the Matter, for that's not the Book-ſeller's Talent, in this ſhort Hiſtory I give you the Life of our New Plot Evidence, in which, conſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dering the Perſon, a Young Fellow, Two Years within his Apprenticeſhip, his Age not above Twenty Two, of ſuch low Extract and Education, take all theſe toge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, perhaps, upon your Reading throughout, you'll ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>knowledge you have met with a Rarety beyond a <hi>Guz<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man,</hi> a <hi>Clancy,</hi> a <hi>Morrel,</hi> a <hi>German Princeſs,</hi> or any of our moſt Famous Impoſtors. I have this farther Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>commendation to make you, That I have made it my Buſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs to get the whole Contents from the Original Parties concern'd, there being but one Story in the whole Book, <hi>viz.</hi> That of Major-General <hi>K</hi>-'s, that I have not at firſt Hand, and that, though at ſecond Hand, I received from very Credible Authority. I have not done (as 'tis cuſto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mary) built a great deal of Fiction upon a ſmall Foundation
<pb facs="tcp:96168:3"/> of Truth. For either from his Maſter, the Merchants, Tradeſmen or others, all Cheated by him, I have ga<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thered my Intelligence all from their own Mouths, and dare confidently averr, there never was a Book of this kind, that the Contents more faithfully adher'd to Truth than this. I have likewiſe inquired into all Affairs in the Gaol, have taken out his Copy of Actions, and re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceived all my Relations in the <hi>King</hi>'s-<hi>Bench,</hi> from the moſt certain Information. One thing is much to be ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mired, He is naturally one of the greateſt Cowards living, and how ſo Low-Spirited a Cheat ſhould attempt ſuch Perillous Impoſtures in ſeveral Nations expoſed to ſo ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny manifeſt Hazards and Dangers attending, is ſome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>what unaccountable. As to the Liſt of the <hi>28</hi> Lords and <hi>15</hi> Commoners Accuſed by him, though I have had a True Copy of 'em, which I keep by me, I durſt not pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſume to put ſuch Honourable Names in Print, though God knows the vile Breath of ſuch an Accuſer has rather done them Honour, than otherwiſe. So bidding you welcome to what Entertainment you'll find, I am</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>Your Humble Servant <hi>A. R.</hi>
               </signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:96168:3"/>
            <head>THE LIFE OF William Fuller, &amp;c.</head>
            <p>TO begin with the Birth of our great Plot-maker, He was the Son of <hi>William Fuller,</hi> of <hi>Milton,</hi> near <hi>Sitingburne</hi> in <hi>Kent,</hi> by occupation a Butcher. His Father, now many years ago deceaſed, had the misfortune to break, and dye a Priſoner in the <hi>Kings-Bench;</hi> his Calamities in a high meaſure imputed to his Wife (our Evidences Mother) who perhaps, to ſay all, was too gay a Dame for a Butchers Wife.</p>
            <p>The Son, under ſuch unhappy circumſtances, through the Fathers Deceaſe, and his Mothers ſecond Marriage, being left in a manner friendleſs, was bound Prentice to Mr. <hi>James Hartley,</hi> Citizen and Skinner of <hi>London,</hi> a Coney wool cutter in <hi>Shooe-lane,</hi> on the 4th of <hi>Jan.</hi> 1686.</p>
            <p>His Introduction to this Maſter was by <hi>Cornelius Harfleet,</hi> Gent. (ſome time ſince one of the Evidences againſt Captain <hi>Crone</hi>) who was a perſon very intimate all along, and for ſome years before our young Coney wooll cutter was born, with both his Father and Mother.</p>
            <pb n="2" facs="tcp:96168:4"/>
            <p>Our Youngſter, though bound, (yet not ſtrong enough tyed) to a Trade, had a roving Head, and all along thought a mechanick employment too inferiour for his more aſpiring Ambition; and therefore, with a great reſtraint upon his nature, made but a hard ſhift to continue under the com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mand of a Maſter.</p>
            <p>He had not been a year and a half in his Apprenticeſhip before his Mother dyed: Now it happening that his Mother, poſſibly not altogether ſo obedient a Wife, as her ſecond Hus<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>band expected, had therefore now and then received a little corporal Correction from his hard Hand, and ſometimes from his harder Foot; more particularly not long before her Death ſhe had been a little diſciplined by a Cudgel, or ſome ſuch Family Inſtrument. The Son therefore upon the news of his Mothers departure, and remembring the Caſtigation ſhe had often received from his Father-in-law, deſires his Maſters leave to go down into <hi>Kent</hi> to inquire into the death of his Mother, alledging that the Blow ſhe had received from her Husband had been the cauſe of her Death; and that he deſigned this Journey only to proſecute his Father-in-law for her Murther.</p>
            <p>The Confidence he expreſt in this matter half perſwaded his Maſter to give him a little credit, and to fancy there might be ſomething in it; and truly in ſo reaſonable a requeſt he could not refuſe him the favour deſired. Our Youngſter reſolving to bring his Evidence hand in betimes, being an early Affidavit-man, moves to <hi>Kent</hi> with no leſs Indignation upon the Anvil, than bringing in Daddy-in-law to the Bar for his Life.</p>
            <p>Down therefore to the Country he goes; and truly makes bold to ſay ſome hard words to his Father, in relation to his Mother; which the Father, as an honeſt man, was very able to anſwer, having really done nothing but what he could juſtifie, his correction to his undutiful Wife being no more than ſhe was able to bear, and leſs than ſhe deſerved. The Son, to do him juſtice in this matter, was not ſo over zealous
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:96168:4"/> for his Mothers death (that being the leaſt of his concern) as deſigning to fright his Daddy out of a ſumm of Money to tye up his Tongue (Evidencing being indeed a Trade, and Money the grand deſign of Swearing.) And therefore all his loud Clamour and the formidable proofs he threatned to bring againſt him, on the account of his Mother, really deſigned more vengeance againſt his Purſe than his Life. If that bled but heartily the other might ſcape whole. But, a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>las, he found his project in vain, for the honeſt Yeoman being hardy enough to ſtand out the ſtorm, and defying what<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ever Juſtice or Judge could do to hurt him, was ſo far from being over-reacht that way, that truly the whole expectation was defeated; our Threatner ſo far ſhort of gaining his point, that he was forced to quit his Cudgels; and after a fortnights ſtaying, come pennyleſs to Town; his Daddys Reputation and Innocence ſtanding both too well fortified againſt all Attacques of this kind.</p>
            <p>Returning home to his Maſter, with much ado he conti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nued with him till the 10th of <hi>June,</hi> 88. the memorable Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bile day for the birth of the Young Royal Hopes, the Prince of <hi>W.</hi> But whether over tranſported with the joys of that mighty Feſtival, or too much elevated with Bonefire ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>king to bring his hand back to any poorer mechanick drudge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry, he took occaſion to walk off, or as ſome call it, run away from his Maſter.</p>
            <p>Thus ſcamper'd, out young Coney-skin cutter could not be heard of by his Maſter, till he found his diminutive Rene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gade a Page to the Right Honourable, and in thoſe days Right Mighty, Earl of <hi>Melfort.</hi> And truly to qualifie him for that dignified poſt, he had taken the then faſhionable Teſt, <hi>viz.</hi> turned <hi>Romiſh</hi> Convert; a young but paſſionate Zealot (as far as the little uſe he had for Religion requir'd) for the Popiſh perſwaſion. In this gay Livery, and in this Honourable Family, being ask'd by ſome friends from his Maſter why he deſerted his ſervice, he made anſwer in theſe very words, That <hi>truly he could not ſerve his great God in a Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teſtant
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:96168:5"/> Family, which was all the reaſon he had to leave his Maſter.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>With this Noble Peer he continued till the days of <hi>Abdica<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion:</hi> but then the greater Buntings all taking wing, this young unfledged Squab was left behind; and whether too ſhame-fac'd (if I wrong him not in laying ſhame to his charge) to return to his Maſter; or for what other reaſons his volatile <hi>Mercury</hi> prompted, he footed it down to his late <hi>Kentiſh</hi> Daddies, though truly not with his late terrible countenance he made his laſt viſit there, having more uſe at preſent of a ſuppliant face; for his ſtock low, and wages and gay Livery both ſpent, he had occaſion of ſheltering under his Roof, and creeping to his Table, as a much humbler Gueſt.</p>
            <p>But, alas, his Reception here proved not ſo favourable as wiſht. His Father in Law having made a ſecond venture, and marryed again, here was a Mother in Law two degrees removed, to be pleaſed: And though the good for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>giving man had forgotten his laſt rough Treatment, and conſequently his Houſe and Table were free for him; howe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver the new Major Domo, the Mother, had not an overfond affection for him; and having unluckily heard of his Romiſh Converſion, through her averſion to Popery, ſhe would by no means ſuffer him to live in the Houſe. The Son, to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>move all Obſtacles of that kind, was ready immediately for Recantation, Renunciation, Abjuration, and what not. He expreſt all the ſorrow in the world for his being miſled, and ſo ſhaking off his Romiſh Superſtition, as eaſily as he could ſhift his Linnen, declared himſelf a penitent Re-convert, and deſired nothing more than his Re-admiſſion to the Boſom of his abandoned Proteſtant Mother Church. But his forſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>king his Husks, could not bring him to the fatted Calf. His Infidel Mother-in-law would by no means be ſatisfied with the reality either of Proteſtations or Tears, nothing belike would convince her of his Re-converſion: So that, in ſhort, here was no home to be had, not ſo much as a Cockloft for him to rooſt in.</p>
            <pb n="5" facs="tcp:96168:5"/>
            <p>Under theſe melancholly circumſtances, his Pride ſome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>what lower'd, he condeſcends to think of returning to his Maſter; and therefore to ſmooth his way home again, (for his affairs ſtood not very well there neither, as with good Reaſon being not at preſent in his maſters very good graces) he writes him a great many pityful Letters, earneſtly implor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of him to receive him again, and making wonderful pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teſtations of Amendment, together with his utterly abjuring his Romiſh Deluſion, and his promiſes of intire Reconciliation to the Church of <hi>England.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>His Maſter being not over eaſily ſoftned, as having but too juſt Occaſion of Reſentment, he writes ſeveral Letters full of the ſame promiſes to Mr. <hi>Harfleet,</hi> and beſeeches his Mediation to his Maſter, Mr. <hi>Harfleet</hi> having a moſt natural Affection for him, (for truly the Boy was extreme like him, ſo like him that you ſhould rarely ſee a Son like a Father) was not wanting in all the good Offices he could do on this occaſion, and in a ſhort time made a perfect Reconciliation, and ſo called home the Fugitive.</p>
            <p>The Wanderer being returned, Mr. <hi>Harfleet</hi> promiſed very laviſhly for his Reformation, and often would viſit his Maſter on the Young mans account. In ſeveral diſcourſes with the Maſter and Patron, between jeſt and earneſt, the Patron was often taxed for being perhaps a little nearer than ordinary related to the Youngſter, and therefore his Zeal in obliging him, looked like a natural Affection towards him. The Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tron, not to belye him, would not plainly own himſelf his Father, but has ſeveral times (ſwore not to uſe the plain Lan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>guage he ſpoke it in) that he had kiſt his Mother a hundred and a hundred times. And truly if you'll take the word of an Evidence in his own Cauſe, 'tis much to be imagined our Minor Evidence is a Gentlemans Graft upon a Butchers Crab<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtock.</p>
            <p>But to return to our Hiſtory; as large as the promiſes have been, and as humble and dutyful a Servant as he intends to be, in a ſhort time he grew a perfect Reprobate; would uſe little
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:96168:6"/> ſhifts out of his Maſters ſmall dealings to miſcount his Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney; kept a private book to enter Wares truſted, and if his Maſter miſt 'em hot, demanded and received the Money for himſelf. He had not kept home this laſt time above 3 months, when, about <hi>Michaelmas</hi> 89, Mr. <hi>Harfleet</hi> came to borrow him of his Maſter for 3 or 4 days ſervice to Major <hi>Kidgell</hi> (af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terwards another Witneſs againſt Mr. <hi>Crone;</hi>) the Maſter kindly complyed and lent him, but Mr. <hi>Harfleet</hi> when he had borrowed him, took care never to ſee him paid again; for in ſix or eight months after his Maſter never ſet eye of him: Inſomuch that he call'd Mr. <hi>Harfleet</hi> to account about it, and receiving no ſatisfactory Anſwer, threaten'd him with no leſs than proſecuting him for Spiriting away his Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vant: Mr. <hi>Harfleet</hi> at laſt gave him the ſatisfaction of ſhow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing him his man again about ſix months after, about <hi>April,</hi> 90, at <hi>Joes</hi> Coffee-houſe in <hi>Salisbury-Court,</hi> in a Rich Coat and all Accoutrements anſwerable, two Footmen at his heels, and the Secretary's Protection in his pocket, and in fine, much too great for a Coney wooll cutter to grapple with.</p>
            <p>In this five months paſt he had been in <hi>France,</hi> as we ſup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſe, and 'twas here that he pick'd up his Plot, the venge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ance whereof ſell firſt upon Mr. <hi>Crone,</hi> when tho' Senior Mr. <hi>Harfleet</hi> and the Junior <hi>William Fuller,</hi> with Major <hi>Kidgwell,</hi> were the Triumvirate Teſtimony againſt him.</p>
            <p>In this advancement he made an extraordinary bluſter about Town; and ſoon after paſt for a Major of a Regiment, par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ticularly to one Dr. <hi>P—n,</hi> a Phyſician in <hi>Kent,</hi> and for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>merly his acquaintance: upon an accidental meeting between em, with a very magiſterial behaviour, and a great many Bravadoes, he talk'd of prodigious Intereſt he had at Court, and profeſſing great friendſhip for the Doctor, he proffer'd him any ſervice he pleas'd to command him there. Would the Doctor be the Queens Phyſician, if he pleas'd to accept of that preferment, 'twas in his power to give it him; with Promiſes as large, as ever <hi>Wickham</hi> made Legacies; therefore deſiring him not to be modeſt, but ask and have, he aſſured
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:96168:6"/> him he ſhould not be three days without it. The Doctor who gave little credit to ſuch Mountain promiſes, yet never<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>theleſs being better bred than rudely to contradict ſo vain a Boaſter, gave him the favourable hearing, and courteouſly replyed, that he was by no means qualified for that Dignity, and whatever favour the Major was able to do him in it, how<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ever his own want of merit would not give him leave to aſpire ſo high. The Major ſwore a great many Oaths, that 'twas his own fault if the Doctor did not accept of his kind<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs; for with a very hearty Oath, he told him he could do it with a wet Finger, nothing more eaſie. The Doctor ſtill modeſtly refuſing, the Major then preſt him to accept of a lower poſt, a Doctor to a Regiment. The Doctor, though really giving little credit to any thing he ſaid, yet ſeemingly ſatisfied with his laſt kind proffer, he thanked him for his great goodneſs, and if the Major would do him the Honour to let him know where he might wait upon him, or write to him, poſſibly he would make bold to embrace his Favour in ſomewhat of this kind, and acknowledge his Friend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip for ſo ſignal an Obligation. The Major hereupon tells him that he would not fail in ſerving him in this, or a greater matter; and as his affairs called him to his command in <hi>Ire<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land,</hi> whether in ſome few days he was upon ſetting forwards, he called for a Pen and Ink and left this Direction for the Do<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cter to write to him, <hi>viz. Direct your Letter for the Honoura<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble Major</hi> William Fuller, <hi>in the Right Honourable the Lord</hi> Sidneys <hi>Regiment.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>This direction did the Doctor keep by him, and has ſeveral times produced it in company, all of <hi>Fullers</hi> own hand wri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting, to laugh at the Impudence of ſo much Pride and Vanity; in a Fellow, that knew the Doctor was no ſtranger to his birth, as a Butchers Son his ſometime Neighbour in <hi>Kent,</hi> and yet thus arrogantly to write himſelf Honourable.</p>
            <p>This Summer he took a Ramble to <hi>Ireland,</hi> where he ſtaid but a ſhort time, however he lived well there, for he never wanted ſome bubble or other to bear his travelling charges in
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:96168:7"/> what Country ſoever; he had either Bills or Shams, or ſome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing, in all places that brought him in a comfortable Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiſtence.</p>
            <p>From <hi>Ireland</hi> he returned, and lived about Town in a pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty ſplendid Equipage, for he had not only ſo many fair words at pleaſure, but likewiſe that innocent Face, that it was hard to ſuſpect him a counterfeit. Here by his ſeveral wheadles he run into a great many Tradeſmens, and others Debts (wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs the large Sums that now lye upon him in the <hi>Kings bench</hi>) for his reſolution, young as he was, was to live apace; for inſtance, he got 50 <hi>l.</hi> into a Mercer in <hi>Covent-garden</hi>'s books. From a paſtry Cooks near St. <hi>James,</hi> pretending himſelf a perſecuted Romaniſt, with ſhams and ſtorys, in money and otherwiſe, he hooked out 80 <hi>l.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>But the neateſt ſham was put upon one Coll. <hi>C</hi>—an old Cavalier and Loyal Officer to King <hi>Charles</hi> I, living not far from <hi>Westminſter</hi> Abby. Spying a Bill upon this Gentlemans door, he comes one day thither in a Chair attended by his man, where deſiring to ſpeak with Madam <hi>C</hi>— the Lady of the Houſe, and pretending himſelf a Country Gentleman newly come out of the Country, and that he had brought his Siſter up with him to ſee the Town, he wanted a Lodg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing for her, and none could pleaſe him like her houſe, for he underſtood 'twas a ſober Family, and 'twould be a great hap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pineſs to his Siſter to have the Converſation of the two young Ladies Madam <hi>C</hi>—Daughters, and truly on that conſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deration he would give her any content, and not ſtand with her for price. Upon this they ſtrike up a bargain, and in 2 days he brings his Siſter in her Country attire. When ſhe had been there a while, he deſired ſhe might go to the danc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing School along with the two young Ladies, being very de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſirous to have her take her education, in all things, from two ſuch fair Examples; but firſt he ſo far inſinuates with the good Collonel and his Lady, as to buy for his Siſter ſuch new Cloaths and other neceſſaries, as might dreſs her up a ſuitable Companion to two ſuch gentile young Ladies, promiſing to
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:96168:7"/> repay all very ſpeedily with gratifications, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> The kind perſwaded old Lady accordingly takes her out and new rigs her from top to bottom, gives her all the breeding of her own Daughters, ſupplys her with every thing, a good Table, fair Lodgings, and what not. This continued above half a year, without one penny payment from the Country Gentleman, the Brother; though continual fair words and promiſes were never wanting, and ſeveral very extravagant Letters came on that occaſion, ſome whereof are as follows.</p>
            <floatingText type="letter" xml:lang="eng">
               <body>
                  <head>The firſt Letter.</head>
                  <opener>
                     <dateline>
                        <date>March <hi>7. 1691</hi>
                        </date>
                     </dateline>
                     <salute>Madam,</salute>
                  </opener>
                  <p>
                     <hi>I</hi> Am almost half distracted that I have thus been forced to diſappoint you; Which I am most heartily aſhamed of: My Banker to whom I committed the care of receiving two hundred Pounds, on <hi>Tueſday</hi> last, I fear is gone off, I have been every day this week to meet him but can never find him within: He ſent me word he would be with me this morning, but is not come, nor is he at his own houſe, which grieves me much; for I have not only diſappointed you but others; but I am reſolved if poſſible to find him, but whether I do or not, at the beginning of the next week I ſhall receive two hundred Pounds more, and then you ſhall com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mand what you pleaſe of me, and now if your neceſſities are great, I am contented to pawn ſome things for you: for I do proteſt I have not by me twenty Shillings, by reaſon I thought my Money ſafe in that fellows hands; but if it is not much to your prejudice, I ſhall bear my loſs the more contented, for I am aſhamed to ſee you till I bring your Money.</p>
                  <closer>
                     <signed>Your humble Servant, <hi>W. Fuller.</hi>
                     </signed>
                  </closer>
               </body>
            </floatingText>
            <p>This Letter though dated 91, was laſt <hi>March</hi> 90. But you have it from the original verbatim, as he penned it.</p>
            <floatingText type="letter" xml:lang="eng">
               <body>
                  <pb n="10" facs="tcp:96168:8"/>
                  <head>The Second Letter</head>
                  <opener>
                     <dateline>
                        <date>Monday March <hi>30, 1691</hi>
                        </date>
                     </dateline>
                     <salute>Madam,</salute>
                  </opener>
                  <p>THE great Obligations you have laid on me, by your care of my dear Sister, and your kindneſs to my ſelf in this time of want, juſtly compels me to acknowledge the Favour; and though it is ſo great, I will ſhortly if poſſible find out ſome way partly to requite it. neither will I ceaſe there, but always whilſt I live will study to be grateful to you The Queen has this morning paſſed an order for all my Moneys to be paid me, and to morrow morning I hope it will paſs the great Seal, the Sum is near two Thouſand Pounds, which I am certain of in a few days, I am juſt now going by her Majeſties Command to a grand Conſultation of Chief Officers, ſo that I cannot poſſibly wait on you; but will on the firſt opportu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tunity, and will not fail ſhortly to oblige you with what Money you deſire. My humble Service to all, I am</p>
                  <closer>
                     <salute>Madam,</salute>
                     <signed>Yours, <hi>W. Fuller.</hi>
                     </signed>
                  </closer>
               </body>
            </floatingText>
            <p>This ſecond Letter, beſides the Rhodomontades in the Contents, I muſt make one farther remark upon. When our great Courtier was ſolliciting at Court for the broad Seal for 2000 <hi>l.</hi> due from the Queen that very day <hi>March</hi> 30.91. he was in a Spunging Houſe, a priſoner for debt, in an Action charged 39 <hi>l.</hi> 17 <hi>s.</hi> And another of 20 <hi>li</hi> From whence the 1ſt of <hi>April</hi> following, he was by <hi>Habeas Corpus</hi> removed to the <hi>Kings-Bench.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>But he ſtaid not there long, for he made hard ſhift (his credit being not quite crackt) to get bail ſoon after.</p>
            <floatingText type="letter" xml:lang="eng">
               <body>
                  <pb n="11" facs="tcp:96168:8"/>
                  <head>The Third Letter</head>
                  <opener>
                     <dateline>
                        <date>May <hi>5. 1691.</hi>
                        </date>
                     </dateline>
                     <salute>Madam,</salute>
                  </opener>
                  <p>I Hope once more of your wonted goodneſs, you will pardon me for not waiting on you ſince yesterday.</p>
                  <p>I could by no means get an opportunity of ſpeaking to the Queen, by reaſon her Majeſty went to viſit the Counteſs of <hi>Suffolk;</hi> I am now going to wait for an opportunity, but ſomething unfit by reaſon I had the misfortune yeſterday to rinch my Foot; if I do not ſuc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceed this day, to morrow by Gods leave, I will go to the A. Bp. of <hi>Canterbury</hi>'s: nor will I miſs of any occaſion to forward my my buſineſs, that I may make both you and my ſelf eaſie, and my Siſter happy. Who am, Madam,</p>
                  <closer>
                     <signed>Your ever Obliged and Faithful Servant, <hi>W. Fuller.</hi>
                     </signed>
                  </closer>
               </body>
            </floatingText>
            <p>You ſee Reader, by what management our young Arts-Maſter put upon the world. For indeed 'twas much at this high ſort of Romance that he gained ſo much credit, and run into theſe numerous debts, in ſo few exttavagant Years. (nei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Kings, Queens, Princes nor Prelates, no names too ſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cred for him) He's an Officer, a Courtier, a Stateſman, a Politician; our beardleſs Privy Councellour call'd to Conſul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tations, and what not: Has Broad Seals and Royal thouſands all at command: Every thing and any thing to look great.</p>
            <p>But to return to our gay Boarding Siſter, you ſee that Cheating and Impoſture may run in a Blood; this young Country Damſel, with the ſame taint in her Veins, a tang of her Brothers Pride, could hold her falſe countenance with no leſs aſſurance, than his own hardned front; and paſs for a Country Lady, eat, drink, and ſleep, with Women of
<pb facs="tcp:96168:9"/> in her falſe trappings of Honour, her unpaid-for Gallantry, their Friend, their Companion and Equal; run on Tick to ſupport her Vanity, and put her Romantick Brother to the expence of ſo many impudent Forgeries, ſuch lying Epiſtles, and all to gratifie a natural Ambition, the itch of a little Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>digality, the Family's frailty.</p>
            <p>But to purſue our Hiſtory; the Collonel and his confiding Lady have not only lodg'd, fed, and rigg'd this Lady Errant, but ſchool'd, pamper'd and danced her too, and all to the Tune of Patience. Our young All-plot having talk'd all, but done nothing, banter'd and ſhuffled ſo beyond all humane ſufferance, that goodneſs itſelf can bear no more; at length they come to this prudent reſult, to attach the gay Rigging in their own hands, the rich garniture they had bought her, and ſo forgiving her her Boarding, Lodging, Schooling and Dancing, they fairly turn'd out the poor Spinſter in her own proper Accoutrements, the Country weeds ſhe came in, to ſhift in the wide world, and exerciſe her own and her Bro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers wheadling faculty for a new Lodging at another Land-lord and Landladys as kind as they had been.</p>
            <p>But this current of Felicity was not always to run on un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtopt; for as a ſmall check to his career, on the fifth of <hi>June</hi> he was ſnapt, and committed once more to the <hi>Kings-Bench.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Now this ſecond time with his Stone-Doublet on, being a little faſter noos'd than before, he was ſoon loaded with 3 or 4 hundred pound Actions, and our Spark too well known to be Bail'd: However, to keep up his port and character, he ſtill carries the Title of a Collonel, and Grandee-like, keeps a man to wait upon him in priſon.</p>
            <p>One Comical paſſage during his confinement is worth the Readers hearing. It happened that one Major <hi>Collingwood,</hi> ſometime a Brigadeer of the Guards, was then his fellow Collegiate; with whom contracting an Acquaintance, and having one <hi>Sunday</hi> invited the Major to Dinner, after a good Treat, and the Bottle going briskly round, (for our Collonel lived nobly) the Major, amongſt other chat, ask'd him very
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:96168:9"/> frankly, how ſo young a man as he, (being then not above 22) came to be made a Collonel? Our young Commander immediately replyed, <hi>For his Services at the</hi> Boyne: And thereupon he makes a moſt heroick relation of Exploits he perform'd there, as a Volunteer, of that extravagant Gallantry equal to Captain <hi>Braggs</hi> Bell-clapper feats at <hi>Buda</hi>) that he told him King <hi>William</hi> took particular notice of him, and in the very heat of the Battel clapping him upon the ſhoulder, <hi>Well</hi> Fuller (ſays the King) <hi>thou art the braveſt young lad in all my Army,</hi> and immediately upon the ſpot gave him a Collo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nels Commiſſion. The Brigadier, who was prepared to ſwal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>low the Jeſt, made anſwer, that no Honour could be ſo great as what was gotten in the Field; and truly he much won<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred the King did not dub him a Knight Bannoret. <hi>But pray noble Collonel,</hi> continues the Major, <hi>were you a Collonel of Horſe or of Foot?</hi> Our young Field-Officer having not his memory about him, could not readily anſwer to that point, but upon ſecond thoughts fancying the Major pincht upon him, <hi>Why Sir</hi> (recollecting himſelf) <hi>do you think</hi> (ſays he) <hi>that I tell you a lye? If you won't believe me, ask my man here, he was there with me, and ſaw the King give me my Collonels Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſion. You Sirrah</hi> (turning to his man) <hi>did not I do ſo and ſo, &amp;c.</hi> (repeating all over again) <hi>and for my Courage and Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vices at that famous Battel did you not ſee the King ſeal me a Coll's Commiſſion?</hi> No, by G—d, replys the man. <hi>How Rogue, Dog, Raſcal!</hi> crys Maſter) and flings a Glaſs of Claret in his Face: The fellow, a ſturdy Lad, his Eyes ſomewhat ſmart<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, and his Indignation a little provoked, returns his Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſters civility by fairly knocking him down. For though nei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Fire nor Steel, Halbert nor Pole-axe could fell him at the <hi>Boyne,</hi> a box o'the Ear was a little too heavy here; ſo riſing up again (for the Fall was not mortal) the Collonel in heat of blood ſomewhat forgetful of his honour, to match his Proweſs with varlets, nevertheleſs enters into ſingle Combat at Loggerheads with his man. In ſhort, a moſt terrible fray enſued between 'em, ſometimes one uppermoſt and ſometimes
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:96168:10"/> t'other; till the Major at laſt, to make a Battel Royal of it, comes in for the third; for having a ſmall walking Crab-tree utenſil in the Room, which he called <hi>Marjery,</hi> he makes bold to lay on. And though he ſeemingly let fly only at the Squire, he let ſome chance drubs fall upon the Knights Shoulders, till maſter and man, to ſhield from this new Aſſailant, drew off at ſome diſtance, and ſtood at bay. The Major, as if his whole vengeance was intended only for the impudent Var<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lets back, began to ſwear as hard now, as he threſh'd before. <hi>Sirrah, Villain, Scoundrel,</hi> (crys the Major) <hi>G— D—mn you for a Son of a Whore, what does your Maſter give you wages for, but to lye for his Credit? if your Maſter had ſaid he had been a Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jor General, were you ſo impudent a Raſcal as to deny it. D— him, let me cut the Rogues Throat.</hi> The fellow pretty well ſatisfied with the Cudgelling already received, would not ſtay for any further engagement, but fairly facing to the right a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bout, marches off with ſome Precipitation, and the Maſter after him, crying very vehemently to the Turn-key, <hi>Stop the Rogue, and by no means to let him go out.</hi> The Turn-key made anſwer, He was no Priſoner, and 'twas more than he could juſtifie to ſtay him. <hi>Ay but</hi> (replies the Collonel, with his Noſe a little dripping) <hi>do you ſee what the Raſcal has done, he is a Dog and a Villain, and has abuſed me.</hi> Nay, for that matter (quoth Turn-key) I am neither Conſtable nor Juſtice of Peace, and ſo opening him the door he gives him the compliment of <hi>[Run Raſcal]</hi> and ſo troops off <hi>Valet de Chambre;</hi> and never found the way back again.</p>
            <p>Our Collonel though loaded with ſo many hundred Pounds (as I told you) nay and though ſo formidable a Hero at the <hi>Boyne,</hi> nevertheleſs found that favour from the Houſe as now and then to be truſted abroad with a ſingle keeper, particu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>larly on the fifteenth of <hi>July</hi> following, he prevailed with one of the Turnkeys to take him abroad to <hi>Weſtminſter.</hi> The Turn-keys wife who had been often promiſed a ſmall token of Love from the Collonel, for her Husbands former civilities to him, was pleaſed to be very high both with the Collonel and Hus<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>band
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:96168:10"/> for Nonperformance of Articles. <hi>Well, what would ſhe have?</hi> Why truly he ſhould preſent her with a <hi>Topknot</hi> and a <hi>Commode.</hi> Very well, the Collonel upon honour would not fail equipping her at one of the Milliners in <hi>Westminster</hi>-Hall. No, troth that won't do, for either ſhe wanted faith, being ſo long promiſed before, or elſe would not truſt to the Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lonels fancy; ſhe had rather have one of her own chooſing. <hi>Then Madam,</hi> replyes the Courtier, <hi>there's a Guinea, pleaſe your ſelf.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>So all parties well ſatisfyed, her Spouſe and his Martial charge the Collonel, move immediately to <hi>Standgate,</hi> and there take Oars for <hi>Weſtminſter</hi> Bridge. At their landing the Turnkey trips out of the Boat firſt, and turning back to look for his Priſoner, he found him ſtept over into a Galley, a boat with 4 Oars, that lay ready for him, and puſhing off with all might and main towards <hi>Whitehall.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The Turnkey immediately bellows at no ſmall rate, in the Kings name, and what not to ſtop him. To take Boat and follow him was in vain, for the Galley was too nimble for any common Oars, beſides the Watermen were of the Col. party. In ſhort he has no way but to leap into the <hi>Thames,</hi> which at that time at the very ſhore was near middle deep. So full cry he flounces in, with all the Expedition he could make af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter him; but all in vain, the Coll. was got to <hi>Whitehall</hi> ſtairs before him; where the Watermen made a fair open Lane for him, whilſt the dripping water-rat came too late to catch him. Some ſmall Hubbub was made at the ſtairs on this occaſion, but all to no purpoſe, our new Courtier was in his own Element, and our Collonel-Hunter ſnapt too ſhort to reach him: and the Jeſt of this pleaſant Adventure went ſo far, that the Queen, inquiring into the occaſion of the Huzzas and Hollows at her watergate, was informed <hi>that only a young Bloodhound, had ſlipt his Collar an Eivdence of hers was got looſe.</hi>
            </p>
            <pb n="16" facs="tcp:96168:11"/>
            <p>The poor Turnkey, poſſibly what with his great Heat within, and his cooling freſh water pickle without, together with his dolorous Affliction for his loſt Priſoner, ſoon fell ſick, and dyed before the end of the month.</p>
            <p>After this nimble conveyance out of his enchanted Caſtle, he began in prudence to conſider, that <hi>London,</hi> and indeed little <hi>England</hi> might ſoon grow too hot for him, and there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore he reſolves for a Ramble for <hi>Flanders:</hi> but before we ſhew you his Adventures there, we ſhall relate ſome particu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lars of his Iriſh Frolicks, which were unhappily forgotten, in his forementioned Iriſh Expedition.</p>
            <p>In <hi>Ireland</hi> by the Title of Squire <hi>Fuller,</hi> his Abode was at <hi>Dublin,</hi> he lodged at a Barbers in <hi>Colledge Green,</hi> where he lived at that extravagant Expence, that notwithſtanding he wheedled one Capt. <hi>Vaud</hi>—a Dutch Officer out of 100 <hi>l.</hi> and ſome other people of conſiderable Sums by drawing of Bills upon an eminent Merchant in <hi>Woodſtreet</hi> (for to countenance his ſhams he made uſe of no little names for his Correſpon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dents) he run in his Landlords and ſome others debts near 100 <hi>l.</hi> more, who having occaſion for their money, and (as with good Reaſon) preſſing a little hard for it, to get his heels looſe to return for <hi>England,</hi> he wheedled in an honeſt man to be bound for it, with Oaths and large promiſes of returning it as ſoon as he came to <hi>England.</hi> But about 6 months after came a moſt miſerable Letter from his kind Bondsman, di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rected for him to a Houſe near <hi>Cheapſide</hi> (whether he uſed to direct his own Letters) deploring his ſad condition, himſelf in <hi>Dublin</hi> Goal, for the Debts he ſtood engaged for him, which he was utterly uncapable of ſatisfying; and that unleſs he returned the Money according to his promiſe, he muſt pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſh in Priſon, and his Wife and Children ſtarve. This Let<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter lying long in their hands, and none of our Wandring Spark at that time to be found, they made bold to open it, and found theſe lamentable contents in it. Had the Letter not been loſt you had had it at length.</p>
            <pb n="17" facs="tcp:96168:11"/>
            <p>At his firſt coming back from <hi>Ireland,</hi> at a Tradeſmans in <hi>London,</hi> he talked of moſt Stupendious Wonder he had per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>formed there, that he was a Collonel of Horſe, had been at the Siege of <hi>Lymrick;</hi> That the Lords, Juſtices had reſolved to make him a Lord Commiſſioner, and as an Earneſt of their Favour, had already given him the Lord <hi>Clanoarties</hi> Houſe, (what he meant by this unaccountable Gibberiſh I under<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtand not) that he was to have Twelve Sub-Commiſſioners under him, the worſt of their places worth 50 <hi>l.</hi> and the beſt 100 <hi>l. per Annum.</hi> But theſe over and above Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>travagant Vapours he only made uſe of, where he thought High Words and Small Senſe would paſs Currant.</p>
            <p>But let us return to our <hi>Flanders</hi> Voyage.</p>
            <p>Accordingly himſelf, with his Man to attend him, and Entitled Collonel <hi>Fuller,</hi> he went down to <hi>Graveſend</hi> to take Shiping for <hi>Holland:</hi> Meeting with Honeſt Capt <hi>C</hi>— that carried the King over, the Collonel ſtruck up with him for 10 Guineas (a Sum bid like a Chapman) to waft him over, ſaying, He was a Collonel and was going to his Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mand: The Captain paid him a more than ordinary Reſpect, and gave him the beſt Treatment his Veſſel could afford. When he came croſs the Water, the Collonel had not Money enough to pay the Sum contracted, but writes a Bill for the Captain to receive 10 Guineas in <hi>Amſterdam,</hi> which at pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent very well ſatisfied the Captain: But when he came to get his Bill accepted, he received an unexpected Anſwer, That they knew no ſuch Collonel, nor had any ſuch Sum ſo payable. This Diſappointment put the Captain into no good Opinion of his Collonel; however, he reſolved to ſay nothing, becauſe he found himſelf bubbled. But his good Fortune in about a Fortnights time after, made him acci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dentally meet his unlook'd for dear Collonel at <hi>Rotterdam.</hi> The Captain makes up to him, and catching him faſt by the Hand, made bold to tell him, that his Bill was not worth a Farthing. <hi>No,</hi> replyed <hi>Fuller,</hi> with a look like a Dead Man, (being not a little ſurprized) <hi>Captain,</hi> ſays he, <hi>I am heartily
<pb n="18" facs="tcp:96168:12"/> ſorry for it, and beg your pardon, here are four Piſtoles for you,</hi> Swearing a great Oath, 'twas all he had; and ſo in haſte took his Leave, whilſt the Captain was very glad to get ſo hand<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>me a Compoſition for a Debt ſo deſperate.</p>
            <p>However this croſs Adventure did not baulk our Knight Errant, and pretending to be a Man of great Quality, no leſs than a Nephew to the Lord <hi>S</hi>—, he carried on the Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>guiſe ſo artfully, and inſinuated himſelf into the Favour of Major General <hi>K</hi>—, whom he ſaw at <hi>Bruſſels,</hi> that he ſtruck up his Heels for 200 Guineas, and was ſo intimate with him as to ride in his Coach with him, the Major General thinking no favour too great for a Perſon ſo nearly Related to his Lordſhip, and one that behaved himſelf ſo much like a Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon of Quality. Till one Day meeting his Lordſhip, he could not forbear telling him how hopeful a Young Gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tleman he had for his Nephew, whom he had the particular Honour to be Acquainted with, not a little priding himſelf in his Friendſhip and Converſation, and giving his Lordſhip a very extraordinary Character of him. My Lord was much ſurpriz'd, and utterly diſown'd any Relation of that Name, and being ſhowed the Perſon, and asking him what Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trey he was of, and which way his Relation to my Lord came in, he ſaid he was of the <hi>Fullers</hi> of <hi>Kent,</hi> that truly he had the Happineſs to be ſomewhat Related, though not ſo near as a Nephew, to his Lordſhip, 'tis true as he much feared, it was his Misfortune to be at preſent unknown to his Lordſhip, however he hoped his Lordſhip would pardon his Boldneſs, in laying claim to ſo high an Honour, it being impoſſible for him to do leſs than pride himſelf, though in the moſt diſtant Affinity to a Family of that Worth and Glo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry as his Lordſhips. My Lord not altogether ſatisfied with this Complement, was pleaſed to ſignifie his Pleaſure, that he deſired him to forbear laying farther claim to his Kindred, for if he did, he would have a Paper pin'd to his <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ck, and have him Bumbaſted by his Footmen through the Camp, that it might be known how little Reſpect he had for his
<pb n="19" facs="tcp:96168:12"/> Nephew. This terrible Anſwer put our Spark into ſome Mortifying Conſternations, and the Major General into ſome ſmall ſurprize, which timely warn'd our Rebuked Gal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lant to walk off to ſhelter from his Lordſhip's Indignation, or rather in prudence to retire from a more formidable dan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ger; ſome hard Queſtions that poſſibly might ariſe about his 200 Guineas, rais'd upon ſo Inſolvent a Pawn as the Credit of his Lordſhips Kindred. And therefore modeſtly with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>drawing before the Major General was prepared to make any ſuch Motion, he left the Room, and in leſs than half an hour after, the Town.</p>
            <p>Here at <hi>Bruſſels</hi> he had all along kept a Coach and Four Horſes, to drive backward and forward to the Camp, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> at Six Crowns a day Expence; though truly his Man <hi>Kent</hi> (for that was his Name) had often in ſeveral Companies, reproved his Maſters Extravagance in not bringing over his own Coach and Horſes, and ſo have ſaved all this needleſs Charge.</p>
            <p>But having occaſion at preſent to move off <hi>incognito,</hi> his Coach and Four Steeds were no further uſeful, the Man and Maſter making the beſt of their way from this dangerous Town, with all the Privacy Requiſite.</p>
            <p>From hence his Pocket pretty well lined he gets to the <hi>Hague.</hi> Here he did not think the bare Title of Coll. which at higheſt amounted but to <hi>Honourable,</hi> ſufficient for the Fi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gure he intended there, and therefore to Tagg his Point with <hi>Right Honourable,</hi> he mounts a little ſtep higher, and Dubs himſelf a <hi>Lord</hi> by the Title of <hi>Baron Fuller;</hi> for it was obſervable, in all his ſhapes; he was very unwilling to part with his Sirname, for whither Major, Collonel, Sir <hi>William,</hi> or Lord in the Front, ſtill <hi>Fuller</hi> brought up the Reer. Here he drove at a high Rate, till Fortune one day unhappily play'd a Sly J<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>des Trick; for when ſeveral of the Higheſt Nobility one Night were at a publick Gaming, our Baron not to ſtand out put in for one of the Fair Gameſters, where 'twas his misfortune to looſe all his Money; and his
<pb n="20" facs="tcp:96168:13"/> laſt ſtake being gone, he pulled out a ſmall Bill of Exchange of 30 <hi>l,</hi> charged by Mr. <hi>John S<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ainsburough,</hi> Hop-Merchant in <hi>Thamesſtreet, London,</hi> upon <hi>Myn Heer Van Wyke</hi> Merchant in <hi>Amſterdam</hi> payable to <hi>William Baron Fuller,</hi> or his <hi>Order,</hi> without any further Advice. This Stake went currant in play, no body doubting a perſon of his Honour, and conſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quently the Bill as ſubſtantial as ready Money. But his Bill, in ſhort followed his Gold; our Gamſter loſt all he playd for. But when the Bill was tendered to <hi>Myn Heer,</hi> here was no Advice (as the Bill mentioned) wanting, for at the firſt ſight he own'd it a Counterfeit, but this not fully ſatisfying the Perſon that tendered it, it happened that an <hi>Engliſh Gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tleman</hi> being by, made bold to tell him, <hi>that he was afraid the Lord was as Covnterfeit as the Bill, for to his certain know<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledge, there was no</hi> Engliſh Nobleman <hi>of that Name, and to confirm what he ſaid, he ſent for the</hi> Preſent State of England, <hi>offering to lay twice the</hi> 30 <hi>pound, that no ſuch Title could be found in the whole Catalogue of the</hi> Engliſh Nobility.</p>
            <p>In this <hi>Flanders</hi> Ramble his Bank ſomewhat ſunk, he happens into Company with one Mr. M.— a Native of <hi>Holland,</hi> and one of the Kings Meſſengers. His Occaſions want<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing a new ſupply, and ſome new Arts to raiſe it, he thought fit to ſtrike in and try his Fortune with this Gentleman. The Diſcourſe between 'em, diſcovering that the Meſſenger ſcarce ever lay ſtill, that he had been upon ſeveral Expedi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions with Expreſſes, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> to ſeveral Courts on his Maje<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſties Account, and conſequently imagining that the Meſſen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ger whoſe Buſineſs lay ſo wide, and himſelf ſo always upon Motion, was undoubtedly an Abſolute Stranger to the Name of, <hi>Fuller</hi> either as Coll. Major, Eſq; Sir <hi>William</hi> or Baron, or any of his Pranks under any of thoſe Titles, and in all likelyhood like to continue ſo; with this conſideration he reſolves to paſs now for Sir <hi>William Fuller,</hi> an <hi>Engliſh</hi> Baro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>net newly come to his Eſtate, his Father Sir <hi>William</hi> not two Years dead, himſelf newly arriv'd in <hi>Flanders,</hi> but juſt come on ſhore, his whole Buſineſs here being to ſpend a
<pb n="21" facs="tcp:96168:13"/> little Money, ſee a few Faſhions, and ſo return home to his Family and Tennants, with all the Priviledges of a Travel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ler, <hi>viz.</hi> To be able to tell Wonders to the homebred Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>try Gentlemen his Neighbours, that ſcarce ever Travelled beyond their own Grounds; to give the two young Ladies his Maiden Siſters a Character of a <hi>Dutch Froe,</hi> and deſcribe 'em the Difference between a <hi>Flandrian</hi> and an <hi>Engliſh Gal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lant;</hi> And likewiſe to ſee a little of a Warlike Campagne abroad, that he might talk Miracles to his Peaceful Brother Militia Captains at Home, and ſee ſome other Foreign No<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>velties, as might furniſh out a modiſh Gentlemans Converſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion at his return: And this truly was all the deſign he had in this Quarter of the World. The Meſſenger much de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lighted with the Gayety of his Humour, expreſt his ready In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clination to do him any ſervice in his Power. Our Sir <hi>Wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liam</hi> returning the Complyment, told him he would take him at his word, and the Favour he would beg of him ſhould be this, to be ſome part of a Guide to him in a Country where he was ſo much a Stranger, deſiring his Directions in his intended Ramble and Travels. The Meſſenger proud of oblidging him in that Civil Courteſie, told him he ſhould want no Inſtuctions of that kind, and indeed 'twould be no little pride to him, could himſelf be his Companion in his Travells; that is, if his own troubleſome Employ would permit: But as that rendered him uncapable of receiving that happineſs, however nothing in his part ſhould be wanting to gratifie ſo worthy a Gentlemen in ſo poor a ſervice, and if he pleaſed to honour him by viſiting an Uncle of his at <hi>Rot<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terdam,</hi> a Brugher of ſome ſmall Faſhion there, he would by a Letter do him that Juſtice to his Uncle, that his Uncles beſt ſervices ſhould be ready to oblidge him in a higher mea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſure then his own weaker Abilities cou'd do. This Gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rous Engagement from Mr. <hi>M</hi>— you may imagine, occa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſioned a Courtly Complimental Anſwer.</p>
            <p>But to ſhorten the Flouriſhing part of our Hiſtory, the Meſſenger and the Baronet grew intimate, and a Recom<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mendatory
<pb n="22" facs="tcp:96168:14"/> Epiſtle was prepared for him to his Uncle; and <hi>Rotterdam</hi> is the next place that our Traveller muſt viſit But before our new Sworn Friends part, the Baronet being in a ſtrange place, and and all his Travelling Treaſure in Bills, and thoſe unfortunately drawn upon Merchants in <hi>Amſterdam,</hi> he has a preſent occaſion for a ſmall ſpill of about 200 <hi>Guelders</hi> to ſupply his pocket till his Receipts from <hi>Amſterdam,</hi> and therefore he makes bold to trouble his Friend for that Diminitive Sum, to be repayed upon Demand with Thanks. The 200 <hi>Guelders</hi> without the leaſt ſcruple were inſtantly furniſht; and our Baronet thus Equip'd ſets forward to <hi>Rotterdam.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Here he is no ſooner Arrived but the Uncle is kind above Imagination, Treats him moſt Sumptuouſly, pays him all the Addreſſes ſuitable to the Quality of his Honourable Gueſt, brings him into the Converſation of ſeveral Rich Mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chants, who all of 'em grew extreamly fond of his Company, being indeed a Darling among 'em. During his ſtay here he ſtrikes in with the Uncle for much about the ſame Sum he had before borrowed from his Nephew the Meſſenger, and does it with that <hi>ala mode de negligence,</hi> that truly 'twas im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſſible to deny him any thing, his pretenſions for borrow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, being only occaſioned by their own over kindneſs to him, for he is ſo highly careſſed by the Uncle and his worthy Friends, that he cannot get looſe from their Embraces to go to <hi>Amſterdam,</hi> to receive his own Bills. Amongſt the ſeveral <hi>Rotterdam</hi> Acquaintance, he grew mightily Intimate with a <hi>Scotch</hi> Merchant who more paſſionately Doated upon him then any of 'em all; with him he grows ſo bold, that having a bill of 300 <hi>l. Engliſh Money</hi> to receive at <hi>Amſterdam,</hi> he gets him to lend him 150 <hi>l.</hi> of the Money, all under the old pretence, that he cannot ſtir yet from his overkind Friends.</p>
            <p>Having thus neatly trumpt upon the doating Sir <hi>Credulous,</hi> he is not content with this pretty handſome Squeeze, but in ſome few days after, privately underſtanding that ſome Af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fairs call'd our <hi>Scotch Adventurer</hi> very ſpeedily to <hi>Amſterdam,</hi>
               <pb n="23" facs="tcp:96168:14"/> he reſolved to paſs the Slur upon him once more. <hi>Sir,</hi> ſays our Baronet, <hi>I am ſo tied by the Leg, that I deſpair of ever getting free from the daily Importunities of my good Friends here, and could heartily wiſh you would take the trouble off my hands, of getting me one of my</hi> Amſterdam <hi>Bills received. Noble Sir;</hi> re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plyed the kind <hi>Scot, I have ſome Occaſions in ſome few Days thither my ſelf.</hi> The Knight ſeemingly tranſported at that good Fortune, made Anſwer. <hi>Nay then Sir, I'll be ſo bold as to make uſe of my worthy Friend, without ſeeking any farther, if you'll pleaſe to favour me with</hi> 50 l. <hi>more, to the Sum you have already pleaſured me with: Pray take this</hi> 300 l. <hi>Bill, and re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceive the Money, and then pay me the Remainder at your Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>turn.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>To make even Money on't, the <hi>Scotch-man</hi> depoſites the Additional 50 <hi>l.</hi> without the leaſt ſcruple, and takes the Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>per Pledge for his Security. Upon this 200 <hi>l.</hi> out of one Pocket, and ſo ſlender a Mortgage for it, our ſerious Sir <hi>Wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liam</hi> begins to conſider that his Affairs are now upon their Critical Point, and therefore ſo orders matters, that that Morning our <hi>Scotchman</hi> moves towards <hi>Amſterdam,</hi> Our Baronet has extraordinary Occaſions to meet ſome Friends newly Landed from <hi>England</hi> at <hi>Helvetſluys,</hi> and to palliate the Buſineſs, he received Letters the very Night before, which laid an Indiſpenſible Obligation upon him of meeting them there, one of the Company being of no meaner a qua<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lity than an Earl, to whom he had the Honour by his Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther ſide to be Nephew. The Duty therefore that lay up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on him on this Occaſion, ſuperſeded all other Obligations, and he muſt be forced to borrow himſelf for ſome few Days from his kind Friend his Landlord, but faithfully promiſing his Return, and withal, not doubting but to bring my Lord his Honourable Relation to <hi>Rotterdam,</hi> whom he was ſenſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble would be highly thankful to him for the great Favours he had heap'd upon his Nephew, he formally takes his Leave.</p>
            <p>No ſooner came he to <hi>Helvetſluys,</hi> but by an accurſed Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>price of Fortune, who ſhould he meet but a particular Friend
<pb n="24" facs="tcp:96168:15"/> of Major General <hi>K</hi>—'s, who privately takes our Sir <hi>William</hi> aſide, and tells him, there were 200 Guineas long owing to the Major General, and which muſt be paid upon ſight: Our Sir <hi>William</hi> was almoſt Thunderſtruck at this Accident, and began a ſoftening kind of a Speech to him; but the Gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tleman who had no leiſure for talking, cut him ſhort in this manner. <hi>Look you Sir,</hi> (ſays he) <hi>the</hi> 200 <hi>Guineas were bor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rowed by fine Words, and Sweet Looks, but hark you, Sir</hi> Knight, <hi>they muſt not be ſo paid. In ſhort, I give you this Choice, either pay down the utmoſt Doit of the Money, or look to be Jayl'd for a Cheat and a Raſcal. I confeſs if thou wert a Gentleman, I would give thee a third Choice; that is, to go into the Field with me, and there give me the pleaſure of cutting thy Throat for thy Villany to my Honourable Friend the Major General; but as thou art a Scoundrel, that's an Honour too great for thee. And ſo, as I told thee before, of the two take thy choice.</hi> The poor Sir <hi>William</hi> at this laſt blow, almoſt knock'd down like one of his Fathers Heifers, for ſome few Minutes ſtood Speechleſs; but at laſt recovering Soul enough to breathe and ſpeak once more, he told the Gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tleman he would give him the utmoſt Satisfaction he was able; that truly he was aſhamed of his Ingartitude to the Major General, but whatever he had deſerved from his hands, he hoped both he and his Friends were Men of ſuch Goodneſs and Worth, that if he ſtrained hard to pay him 200 Guineas, they would graciouſly pleaſe upon his hum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble Supplication, which he would make upon his Knees, to ſeek no farther Satisfaction nor puniſhment for his faults. That therefore he hoped the Gentleman would be ſo kind as to be ſilent in the matter, leaſt the expoſing of him might be his utter ruin, which alas would be a poor Trophy for ſo noble a Gentleman as the Major General. Nay, ſays the Gentleman, pay but the Mony, you owe my Friend, and cheat all the World beſides in the Devil's Name. For my my own part, I'll be ſo far from expoſing thee, that I'll rather puſh on the Jeſt than baulk it.</p>
            <pb n="25" facs="tcp:96168:15"/>
            <p>Upon this ſmall Comfort, and ſome farther Aſſurances from the Gentleman on the ſame Account, he made hard ſhift, from the 200 <hi>l.</hi> from the kind <hi>Scot</hi> (which, as good Fortune would have it, was yet untouch'd,) and the addi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of a Gold Watch, to ſatisfie the whole ſumm demand<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed. The Gentleman ſeeing the Moveable' <hi>viz.</hi> the Watch in too, to help up the ſumm, began to have ſome Commiſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ration upon him. Well, <hi>poor Raſcal</hi> (ſays he) <hi>I will not un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>do thee quite, there's five Gueneas back again for thee for work<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Tools, till thou makeſt the next Bite for more;</hi> and ſo, true to his Promiſe, without words o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> noiſe he takes his leave.</p>
            <p>Our poor ſimple Travellor reduced to this ſmall ſtake of five Guineas, is not a little diſconſolate at his Calamity; however conſidering his Credit's above Deck, though his Pocket is a little under Hatches, 'tis ſome Mitigation to his greif; and reſolving to truſt Fortune once more, he plucks up a Spirit; puts on a good Face, and looks out ſharp for new Game.</p>
            <p>He has no ſooner ſhook off all Care, and baniſh'd all Sor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>row, but he happens to meet with two or three <hi>Engliſh</hi> Mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chants waiting for a paſſage to <hi>Harwich,</hi> he ſoon makes one with 'em; where bearing up the Port of an <hi>Engliſh</hi> Barro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>net, in an hours Converſation he begins to be a familiar Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quaintance, talks much of his Travels, that he was a great Man at Court, formerly the late Queens Page, but ſince he came to Age, and his Eſtate, a Gentleman of Their now Majeſties Bed-Chamber; that he was returning for <hi>England,</hi> &amp; expected a King's Yatch for his Paſſage, to which theſe <hi>En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gliſh</hi> Gentlemen ſhould be welcome, and that he had by Letters ordered his Coach and ſix Horſes from his Seat at <hi>Cobhamhall,</hi> to attend him at <hi>Harwich.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>This Account from our Bed-Chamberman, procured him a great many Legs and Scrapes from the Merchants, who in Duty bound, returned his Honour a kind Acknow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledgment for the Favour of his Yatch, they having deſign'd their Paſſage by the Packet Boat. No, by no means, he muſt beg that Favour of 'em; and not only ſo, but to take a part of his Coach from <hi>Harwich</hi> to <hi>London.</hi> He
<pb facs="tcp:96168:16"/> had at preſent only one Servant attending him, and the Diverſion of good Company, would be an Obligation of the higheſt value.</p>
            <p>The Merchants were in no ſmall Confuſion at this Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>travagant Generoſity from a Stranger, and a Perſon of his Rank. But waiting for our Royal Yatcht, our Expectants were all diſappointed, Wind, Tide, or ſome other croſs Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cident was in fault, for no Yatcht came: inſomuch that in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtead of a Kings Cabin, our Grandee was forced to make one with the Merchants in the homely Packet-Boat. Our ſhort Voyage quick Diſpatcht, no ſooner were we all ſafe at Port, but Inquirie at the <hi>Inns</hi> in <hi>Harwich</hi> was made for a Coach and Six Horſes that waited for Sir <hi>William Fuller,</hi> to which being anſwered in the Negative, that no ſuch Coach was or had been there; He fell into a great Paſſion, called his Steward a great many Rogues and Villains for this im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pudent neglect of his Commands, that his Letter that order<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed his Coach, he was certain he muſt have received; that there was no Wind or Tide could hinder his Coach from Traveling, whatever they had done to diſapoint him of his Yatcht; that the Negligence of his Servants was unpar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>donable, and when he ſaw 'em he ſhould reward 'em ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cordingly. Now one thing I ſhould have told you, he had Struck in with one of theſe Merchants for Ten Guineas; for a Perſon of his Quality, to want ſo poor a Sum, was only thro his Diſtance from home, and the long ſtay abroad, that had lickt him up ſome conſiderable Hundreds more than he Expected. Thereupon being defeated of his Coach and Six Horſes, and thereby not only unable at preſent to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pay the Ten Guineas, but what grieved him more, that he could not obliege his worthy Friends as Engaged, he begg'd a Thouſand Pardons of 'em.</p>
            <p>One little Eſcape I had almoſt Omitted. In the <hi>Packet-Boat</hi> he met with one who very intimately knew him, <hi>viz.</hi> when he was my Lady <hi>Melforts</hi> Page. This Perſon at pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent under ſome Cloud, being a Noblemans Diſcarded Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vant, made bold to borrow of his old Croney a Crown; and upon this Encouragement, once or twice more requeſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed
<pb n="27" facs="tcp:96168:16"/> a further Favour of two or three Half Pieces of him, which our prudent Sir <hi>William</hi> to ſtop ta<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ling pretty willing<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly lent him; but at laſt hearing his Fellow Traveller; the gay <hi>Baronet,</hi> talk at that Prodigious Rate to his Mates the <hi>Engliſh</hi> Merchants, he whiſpered him once more and deſired to be pleaſured with a Brace of Guineas. Our Knights Fund at this time none of the ſtrongeſt, and good Nature ſome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>what tired with ſo troubleſome a Petitioner, he was pleaſed to refuſe this importunate Suppliant. Upon which his hum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble Addreſſor changing his Note, began to talk hard words, that if he denyed him this Favour, he ſhould take the bold<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs to cackle, and make ſome not overgrateful Illuſtrations to his Merchant Friends, upon the true Birth and Pedegree of their Honourable Friend Sir <hi>William, &amp;c.</hi> Our Sir <hi>William</hi> a little nettled, but not out braved with all theſe threatnings, wiſely runs to his Friends, and crys Whore firſt; tells 'em that an impudent fellow in the Boat whom he never ſaw be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore, and on whom he had beſtowed ſome Charity, had the Inſolence to ask to borrow two Guineas of him; which being denyed him, the ungrateful Villain with that fore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>head of Braſs, that he had never mett with in his whole Life, pretended to aſperſe him with a parcel of Lyes and Forge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ries, ſuch as he almoſt trembled to hear; that the Rogue would come and tell his worthy Friends forſooth, that he was a Cheat, ſome pittyful Scoundrel like himſelf, and other ſuch impudent Stuff that made his Hair ſtand on End but to Repeat. The Merchants were much concerned at this hi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deous Affront to their Honourable Friend: And in ſhort the Matter came to a Tryal of Skill; For the whole Life and Pedigree of this pretended Knight was reap'd up before 'em, in which the Knight ſo out brav'd all the poor Accuſer could ſay, that he clearly carry'd the Cauſe; inſomuch that at laſt it came to a Challenge between the Knight and the Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>peacher, in which the two Merchants on the Knights ſide, and two other Paſſengers for the other Principal, were to have been their Seconds; But the Quarrelling Part before they came a Shore was huſht; and though this Accuſer took the Merchant (that had lent him the Ten Guineas) aſide,
<pb facs="tcp:96168:17"/> and bid him have a care of the Impoſtor, engaging to make out the Truth of all he had ſaid; Nevertheleſs, our Sir <hi>Wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liam</hi> held that intire Aſcendant that he would not believe one Syllable againſt him.</p>
            <p>But to return to <hi>Harwich.</hi> The Coach and Six Horſes be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing wanting, the Knight and his Companions came in a hired Coach to <hi>London;</hi> and there taking leave, he Invited 'em to meet him at Dinner at a Tavern in <hi>Queens-Street</hi> near <hi>Cheapſide</hi> on <hi>Thurſday</hi> ſevenight following, againſt which time he would have a fat Buck from his Park at <hi>Cobham Hall</hi> to entertain 'em, and then pay the Ten Guineas borrowed. The Merchants accordingly with ſome Friends (one where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of an Oyle Man in <hi>Alderſgate-Street</hi>) met at the Tavern on the day, but to their Supriſe found neither Dinner, Veni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon, nor Knight provided. This Defeat ſtrangely exaſpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rated the Merchant that lent him the Ten Guineas, that more out of revenge than value of the Money, he made it his Buſineſs to hunt him through the whole Town, till at laſt he fixt him at a Houſe over againſt the <hi>Charterhouſe:</hi> here he found it curſed hard to get at him, for he lived upon the Sculk, came in Late, and went out Early; however, re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſolved to Snapp him, he came with his Officers at 11 one Night, reſolving to keep 'em upon the watch all Night, him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf, and his Oyle-man Friend with him. The Spark was then going to Bed, but his man diſcovering ſome Perſons at the Door, which he fancied waited for his Maſter, he ſlipt to the Conſtable and Watch, and told 'em there were Thieves deſigned to break open ſuch a Houſe; the Conſtable and his Mirmidons thus Allarm'd, came to do their Duty; when ſeing their Subſtantial Neighbour the Oyle-man, out of the Gange of Thieves, upon Examination they found out the whole Roguery: And inſtead of Apprehending joyned with them, and ſo far prevailed with the Landlord as to open his Door, and let in the Officers; who Arreſted him in his Chamber, and hurried him to a <hi>Spunging-Houſe,</hi> from whence on the 18th of <hi>November</hi> laſt he was by <hi>Hab Cor.</hi> re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moved to the <hi>Kings-Bench.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>It ſeems now that all his old Arreers are to be paid at once,
<pb n="29" facs="tcp:96168:17"/> for on the 18th of <hi>November</hi> laſt, he was brought over to the <hi>Kings Bench</hi> by <hi>Habeas Corpus,</hi> and Lodged at one of the <hi>Tipſtaffs</hi> Houſes, under careful Tuition. The <hi>Marſhal</hi> was pretty well pleaſed that they had retrieved their Fugitive, and giving him a viſit, he asked him the Reaſon why he made ſo ungrateful a Return, for his Keepers kindneſs in <hi>July</hi> laſt, in making that former Eſcape: To which he im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pudently made Anſwer, <hi>he did it by the Queens Special Order.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>In theſe Melancholy Circumſtances, his Projecting Head, about the end of <hi>December,</hi> put him upon Addreſſing to the <hi>Houſe of Commons,</hi> concerning his new Diſcovery; The Cre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dit he thought he had gained in Mr. <hi>Crones Diminitive Cauſe,</hi> made him preſume upon the Foundation of the Inconſide<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rable Truths delivered <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>hen, to raiſe Airy Caſtles and Moun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain Prodigies now. Accordingly, he writes two Letters to the <hi>Speaker,</hi> whereupon, <hi>January</hi> the firſt, he was Ordered by the <hi>Marſhal</hi> of the <hi>Kings Bench,</hi> to Attend the Houſe on the <hi>Monday</hi> following.</p>
            <p>According to that Order, he appeared before the Houſe the 4th. of <hi>January</hi> and had a Hearing before 'em, upon which was reſolved, that an humble Application ſhould be made to His Majeſty, that he would pleaſe to Grant to Mr. <hi>Fuller</hi> a Blank Paſs for two perſons, for their ſafe coming from beyond Sea, or any other place hither to give their E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vidence, and for their ſafe Protection while they are here, and their ſafe return if deſired.</p>
            <p>On the 22d, of <hi>February,</hi> the Houſe being acquainted by the <hi>Marſhal</hi> of the <hi>Kings Bench,</hi> that Mr. <hi>Fuller</hi> was very ill, and not able to attend the Houſe according to Order, ſeve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral Members were appointed to repair to him, and take his Examinations and Information upon Oath, to ſecure his Papers, and Examine him who his Witneſſes were, where they lived, and where to be found. And the Houſe being farther acquainted by one of the Members, where the ſaid Witneſſes would be that Morning, the ſaid Member was ordered to go to the place and bring 'em to the Houſe.</p>
            <p>On the 23d of <hi>February,</hi> one of the Members of Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment (according to the order of the day) Reported, that
<pb n="30" facs="tcp:96168:18"/> the Members appointed, had repaired to Mr. <hi>Fuller, Had taken his Examination and Information upon Oath, and ſecured his Papers, and Examined who his Witneſſes were, and where to be found.</hi> Which Papers and Examinations were delivered at the Table Sealed, and there opened and Read by the whole Houſe. Mr. <hi>James Hayes,</hi> and <hi>Coll. Tho. Dalavell,</hi> be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing mentioned by <hi>Fuller,</hi> to be the two Witneſſes, and he having directed where they Lodged, and deſcrib'd 'em to the Member that had repaired to him; ſeveral Members of the Houſe were Ordered to bring the ſaid Perſons with them: and accordingly the Members appointed went, and Return<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed with this Report to the Houſe, that they had been at the place directed by <hi>Fuller,</hi> but upon Inquiry there, both of the ſaid Perſons Names and the Deſcriptions of their Perſons, they could not hear of any ſuch Perſons to have Lodged either at that place, or the adjacent Houſes, the Perſons who owned the ſaid Houſes, being all ignorant of any ſuch Perſons Whereupon the Houſe ordered that Mr. <hi>Fuller</hi> ſhould procure his ſaid <hi>Two Witneſſes to attend the Houſe to Morrow Morning at Ten a Clock peremptorily.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>But that Morrow being a Day quite out of his Alma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nack, and the whole Juggle and Shuffle now plainly appear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, it was declared by the whole Houſe, <hi>February</hi> 24. <hi>Nemine contradicente,</hi> that the ſaid <hi>Fuller was a notorious Impoſtor, a Cheat, and a falſe Accuſer; that he had ſcanda<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liz'd Their Majesties and their Government, abuſed the Houſe, and accuſed ſeveral perſons of Honour and Quality; and that an humble Addreſs ſhould be preſented to his Majeſty, to com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mand his Attorney General, to proſecute him accordingly.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>After this juſt Brand ſet upon him, and the proſpect of a condign puniſhment, now ſpeedily to attend him, I ſhall only inform the Reader, that when his ſwearing Hand was in, he accuſed no leſs than 28 Lords, Spiritual and Tempo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral, and 15 Commoners, moſt of which of no mean Quality.</p>
            <p>I ſhall only add a little Account of his Deportment in his Confinement; firſt, he affected his old Title of Collonel ſtill; nay, ſuffers himſelf to be call'd Collonel to this very day. Upon the Credit he thought he ſhould get by his
<pb n="31" facs="tcp:96168:18"/> Plot, he bore himſelf with a very high ſtrut and big look to the Tipſtaff his Landlords Son, and others; he offer'd 'em places in his Gift at the <hi>Cuſtome-Houſe,</hi> or where they pleaſed, of near 200 <hi>l.</hi> a Year. One day he had the Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pudence to write a Letter to the Arch Biſhop, who ſmil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing at the Confidence of the Man; a Gentleman then at<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tending his Grace, for the Humour ſake, came to viſit him at the Tipſtaffs, which happening at Noon-time, he was at Dinner with 2 Fowls in a Diſh, and two young Women at Table with him. The Gentleman told him, that he underſtood he had written a Letter to the Arch-Biſhop. Yes Sir, replyed our Coll. and I have good Rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon to write; here am I ſerving the King and the Church, and the Nation, by diſcovering the Plots and Deſigns of their Enemies, and whilſt I am doing 'em all this ſervice, I am kept here and Starved. <hi>How</hi> (replyed the Gentleman) <hi>two Fowls, and two Miſtreſſes, and complain of Starving! Troth, Sir, I think one Fowl, and one Miſtreſs at a time, would make ſhift to keep you from that Danger.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>In his Sickneſs, which diſabled his Attendance upon the Houſe, he ſlily indeavour'd to inſinuate a Belief that he was poyſon'd, imagining (as 'tis to be ſuppoſed) that ſuch a Suggeſtion might have credited his Evidence, by being thought ſome deſign of the Plotters, to ſtifle his Diſcovery. A Day or two after this laſt Vote of the Houſe of Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mons, his pretended Indiſpoſition continuing, perhaps in earneſt, that mortifying Vote being ſufficient to make him ſick indeed, Mr. <hi>Th</hi>— an Eminent priſoner, a perſon that had given a little too fond an Ear to our Plot Witneſs (though at preſent ſomewhat aſhamed of his over-Credulity) at his own Charge ſent a Phyſitian to him. And at almoſt Mid<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>night after, the Lecturer of the Pariſh was call'd to him, and deſired to pray by him, who told him plainly, <q>That if he would firſt deſerve his Prayers, he ſhould have 'em, <hi>viz.</hi> if inſtead of the pretended Poyſon he was ſick of, he would diſgorge the true Poyſons he had poyſon'd the Nation withal,</q> and own the Motives and Cauſes why he Accuſed ſo many Innocent Perſons of Honour, then he ſhould have
<pb n="32" facs="tcp:96168:19" rendition="simple:additions"/> the Heartieſt Prayers he could make for him. But till then he muſt excuſe him, and ſo left him.</p>
            <p>The next Morning the Curate was ſent for, to intreat him to do that Chriſtian Office, which the Lecturer had refuſed him, which the Curate readily conſented to. And after ſome very Hearty Prayers ſuitable to the Sick Conſcience he pray'd for, he modeſtly preſt it home to him, concerning the many Perſons of Honour he had Accuſed, till at laſt he frankly confeſt he had done 'em a great deal of wrong, <hi>For all he had Sworn was not of his own Knowledge, but only from Hear ſay.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>He wheadled Dr. <hi>Oats</hi> out of Fifteen Pound (but upon what pretence our Examinants are not informed) and a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mongſt other Actions lyes charged at his ſuite for 30 <hi>l.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>It happned that two of the Waiters either in the Spirit of Ale, or Spirit of Prophecy, were one day ſo overhardy, as to talk little of our great Evidence; that they believ'd he wou'd prove a ſecond <hi>Dangerfeild,</hi> and his higheſt Preferment end in a Pillory or Carts-Taile. This coming to his Ears, he fell into that Mortal Dudgeon againſt 'em, that the <hi>Marſhal</hi> was forced to turn them both out of their places, and glad he could come off ſo cheap; though 'tis true, ſince the laſt <hi>Houſe of Commons</hi> Vote, he has Reſtored them again.</p>
            <p>But above all, one thing is ſtrangely Remarkable, that notwithſtanding, he lay charged with ſo many Actions; one of 'em particularly of a 1000 <hi>l.</hi> at the <hi>Marſhals</hi> Suite for his laſt Eſcape; and as ſlippery a Prank as he had plaid 'em before; Nevertheleſs he had that ſtrange Influence on the <hi>Tipsſtaff</hi> that had him in Cuſtody, to be ſeveral days truſted abroad without a Keeper. For inſtance within Six Weeks laſt, he made three Several Viſits to an old Friend in <hi>Wood-Street</hi> (where the whole Family will Atteſt it for Truth) without any Waiter Attending him. Now certainly he muſt either have ſome mighty Hopes of doing Wonders by his Plot; or elſe muſt lye under ſome ſtrange Infatuation; that he did not run away from ſuch a Lord of Debts; that 'tis impoſſible he can look for leſs than ſtarving under 'em. For I dare Swear for him, 'twas not out of pure Honour, to be true to his Parole that made him ſlip ſo many Occaſions of Eſcaping.</p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
